Interviewer: Is family always more important than friends?
Alice: I think, for the majority of people, that is the case,
but I also think we can’t deny the fact that families come in all shapes and sizes.
We’re not just that, kind of, parents, children, er, format any more, because,
you can’t deny that, maybe, children have not had, like, the best upbringing,
and they feel like they’ve, they’ve had to, you know, separate from their parents,
or vice versa because of external things.
Um, so, they form these attachments with their friends that become like a family to them
and become incredibly important.
James: Yeah.
Alice: Um, there are people that I know now, who, they are, um, what’s the word?
Um, they’ve broken off from their, their parents because of things that have happened to them,
um, but they have formed these attachments to their friends that are thicker than blood, almost.
James: Yeah. That’s really interesting, um, it’s an unusual perspective, but I agree with you.
Um, I think there’s also, for me, at least, there’s a kind of stage-of-life thing, as well, around this.
So, when I was younger, when I was in my teens and my twenties, my friends were really,
really central to what I was doing and how I was feeling and took up all my, um, thinking.
And as I’ve got older, and had, you know, kids and a family, that’s kind of taken centre stage.
And while while I still, you know, love my friends they just don’t occupy as central a,
a part of my life as they used to.
Um, but obviously different people will have different, um, experiences of that as well.
Debbie: Yeah, I, I totally agree with you.
When I was younger, friends were really important, once my children came along,
that was my main focus.
Everything that I had was invested in them,
so therefore my family unit became the most important thing.
Now I’m older, things have changed in my life.
Recently having gone through a marriage break-up,
I have now discovered that as much as my family have been there for me,
and my two sons have been my rocks, and they really have been amazing,
my friends are the ones that have got me through everything,
because they are of the same age as me, the same generation.
So, they understand what’s going on with me, they understand why I’m feeling the way I’m feeling,
and so, I feel more comfortable with them and I’m able to respond to any advice
that they might give me.
Um, so as much as I love my family, right now in my life my friends are more important to me.